Kevin Dias

Full-Stack Software Engineer Portfolio | GitHub Warwick, RI kevin.vi.dias@gmail.com

Inspired by the complexities of the web, its design, and its integration to create intuitive, clear, and concise user experiences. Writer-turned-engineer focused on developing excellently communicated web stories for a diverse set of user backgrounds.

Education

General Assembly, June 2022, remote

A.S. Computer Science, May, 2021, Community College of Rhode Island - Warwick, RI

B.A. Literary Arts, 2010, Brown University – Providence, RI

Skills

Languages: CSS, HTML, EJS, JavaScript, JQuery, Python, React

Frameworks: API Implementation, Bootstrap, Bulma, Django, Express, Node.js

Databases/Repositories: ERDs, GitHub, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Potpourri: Excellent communication skills, meeting facilitation, mental health First Aid, mentoring

Work Experience

General Assembly Fellow, March 2022 - June 2022

- Developed a <u>browser-based card game</u>, employing HTML, CSS, JavaScript and JQuery.
- Created an <u>Instagram-like site</u> utilizing the MEN stack (Mongoose, Express, Node), styled with the Bulma CSS framework, and deployed using Heroku
- Produced a <u>Final Fantasy™ fan site</u> applying the MERN stack (Mongoose, Express, React, Node), complete with user authentication through the application of React Redux
- Constructed a <u>Board Game Geek-inspired site</u>, using Django/Python and BGG.com's API

Community College of Rhode Island, August 2016 - June 2021

Administrative Assistant to the Dean of Health and Rehabilitative Sciences

- Redesigned 13 health science programs' hard-copy admissions requirements for the web, increasing applications per program by a minimum of 30%
- Coordinated COVID testing event for 800+ students and staff, collaborating with the Department of Health and school leadership, completing task within 30 days

Volunteer Work

Youth-to-Youth Leadership Program, 2002 - Present

- Fostering leadership, teambuilding, communication and problem-solving skills in an active, hands-on, fun, positive group environment with a focus on facilitation/mentorship
- Staff trainer, educating youth and adults on proper facilitation techniques, how to respond
 to difficult group dynamics and uncomfortable situations, and to help direct the 4-day
 event with over 500 individuals in attendance